Previously onDead City.
Titicaca wants to know when
the sweet jams can return.
Stop pretending like you can
talk to those toothless freaks.
Luis said he's gonna quiz
me on this.
I don't think I'm ready yet.
You are. One breath.
one motion.
We could plow
Central Park. grow more food.
bring in even more people.
You don't want just more people.
You want good people.
And I hate to be the one
to break it to you.
I don't know
that there's a lot of
good people left.
I guess we'll find out
♪ And your heroes
and villains ♪
♪ Sometimes look the same ♪
♪ You lost 'em all
in Paris ♪
♪ Somewhere near
the Seine ♪
♪ It's so easy
when you're on the couch... ♪
Oh. hey.
-Need that?
-Oh!
Thanks.
Is Negan around?
Yeah. big man's upstairs.
Is that from a deadie
you dropped outside?
'Cause I could use a few
for my CLVFC.
Negan mentioned your food chain.
Oh yeah.
See. you got the maggots.
and they just eat up the rot.
They just strip it all down
to nothin'.
And then out of
that nothin' comes...
somethin' good.
And that's somethin'
that can sustain life.
You know. nothin' wasted.
not even the deadies.
My dad used to say
the same thing.
about farming.
Oh yeah?
Everything that
you put into the soil
comes back to you.
Sounds like Papa Magpie
had his finger on the pulse.
Dirt don't lie.
Now whether it comes from
seed or bone...
Yesterday's somebody.
If you treat it right.
man. it is gonna pay you back
every time.
It's one of the last promises
left in this world.
as far as I'm concerned.
Well. that and how shoelaces
always wear out
before the boot.
What is up with that?
-Negan's upstairs?
-Yes ma'am.
No. no. no. no. no.
Hey. buddy. come on.
Rein it in.
Hey. cut that shit out.
You are gonna screw up your arm
all over again.
Oh. you gotta stop!
Maggie?
Can you toss me that duct tape
at the end of the bar please?
Cockenspiel. stop.
What are you doing?
Would you please hold it in?
Hey. is "pretty" worth losing
an arm over. kid?
Negan. can you hold him down
while I duct tape him?
No.
So are you here to tell me
about your big night?
I saw your little light show.
Well. I figured we should
put up a welcome sign.
Did you hear about
the other thing?
The Dama killed herself.
Alright. well.
I guess she made her choice.
Mm. I thought I'd feel...
I don't know what
I thought I'd feel.
Well. I don't know.
I think that
you should feel good.
The old hag.
she did you a favor.
Alright. is there anything else
from the daily debrief
that will be of interest to me?
Season is turning.
Everybody is
clearing Central Park.
We got to plant
before the frost.
And we can certainly
use your help.
That's a good one.
Oh. you're being serious.
I can't. I got some shit
to tend to in my own house.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
Alright. look.
I am done with you
playing patty-cake
with two flesh sacks
in your bar all day.
So you killing Scraps here?
It's the first step in you
becoming a half civilized
human male who can
still get laid
before the moths finish eating
that sock puppet
you call a dick.
Your dick's a freaking
decorative spoon.
Brother. do it.
Okay.
Help... me.
She's not even a danger.
brother.
I need to know
that I can trust you
if shit hits the fan.
Yeah. actually. fuck this. man.
Fuck this.
Actually. fuck you.
'Cause I take out
plenty of deadies
for the chain. brother.
The real question is.
what is it to you
if I got some
I talk to sometimes?
Alright. well the first thing
I'd say to that is
they're not people.
But wait a minute.
what about Cole Brewer
or fucking Razer McNab?
Are those people?
Let me answer that for you.
Negan.
No. they're god damn
video game characters.
Okay? I was holed up all alone
for a fucking eternity.
What is your excuse?
Shit.
That's Fabian's flare.
He must have spotted something
on the river.
Let's go.
Whoa! I wasn't expecting
the Fuckyouville
welcoming committee.
Don't get it scrambled.
neighbor.
You gamble on people.
We protect our pile.
Just so happens the shit
you kick loose
rolls downhill.
We've got to get
these people to the hospital.
You're gonna be okay. alright?
Is anyone bit?
No. This was people.
A crew out of Newark.
Been raiding us for years.
Taking everything they could.
We saw the statue last night
and were packing up
what little we had left
to check it out.
But they hit us at dawn and set
the whole damn place on fire.
Belleville ain't nothin'
but ashes now.
So you followed the light?
Suspected it might be a trap.
Took a chance on the hope
it meant what it used to.
Does it?
It does.
Give me your tired. your poor.
and your huddled masses. right?
Okay. listen up. everyone.
I need every able-bodied person
to help bring the wounded to
the hospital.
Streets are a mess.
Cars are not getting through.
so it is walk or be carried
all the way down Amsterdam.
Hey. thank you for your help.
I still think lighting
that statue was a bad idea.
It doesn't mean I won't do
my job.
Hey. Bauer.
These Newark assholes.
are they
the kind to come after you?
Because if they're coming.
they're coming after all of us.
We need
to get everyone somewhere safe.
Injured to the hospital.
the rest of these people
safe to an apartment.
I'm gonna get word to
the armory.
get weapons and backup.
After that.
head to the hospital.
You handle the home front.
I handle Newark.
-Okay.
Really?
So you're just gonna play
Florence Nightingale
when a boatload
of bad people show up?
Yeah. 'cause Renata knows
what she's doing.
Does she?
She kept her
family alive for 15 years
without killing anybody
or using an army.
Right. until The Croat
showed up.
And she lost twoof hers.
How many have you lost?
When she cracks. Maggie.
and she will.
then it's gonna be on you
to keep your son breathing.
So the sooner you step up.
the safer we'll all be.
Green is for
non-life-threatening injuries.
If they can walk. they're green.
If they can talk.
they're purple.
And red? Red means
handcuff your patient
to their bed. okay?
Let's go! Go.
Come on.
You've gotta be
the youngest doctor
I've ever seen.
I'm just
an apprentice. actually.
I just
grabbed it in the fire.
I don't know why.
You can't play with one domino.
It's a game?
Yeah.
It's a family tradition.
Out of all of them.
I grabbed this one.
It's bad luck.
Big six.
That's what
my uncle always said.
Well. you got here.
Maybe your luck's starting
to turn around.
Mm.
Sure as hell
didn't expect all this
when we followed the light.
It's a good place.
And with a great doctor.
And he'll set your arm
once things die down.
Do not fucking fire
unless I fucking signal.
-You got it?
-Whatever you say. boss lady.
Put your weapons down. everyone.
Weapons down.
Luis! Stab wound from Newark.
Take her to trauma one.
Whoa! Hell no!
You put us in here with them.
they're gonna kill us.
Y- y-you're making a mistake.
Newark attacked us.
and they'll attack you.
And you've got too much to lose.
Newark washed up even worse off.
They're saying
that Belleville attacked them.
Alright. so we've got
to treat enemies side by side.
I think until we figure out
what's going on.
the only thing to do
is to help them all.
I confiscated Belleville's
weapons already.
And I took Newark's.
We're gonna post up guards.
and we'll minimize the danger.
We turned on that light.
They are here because of us.
I have to figure out
who can stay.
But if our people get hurt
before I can do that. I-
That is not gonna happen.
I'm not gonna let it happen.
That's my job.
Your job is to make
the best choice for all of us.
More incoming.
Can't we give her something more
for the pain?
That was the last
of our morphine.
At this rate. we're gonna
burn through most of
our supplies
before the day is done.
Patients won't survive
surgeries like this.
They're gonna die of shock.
So what can we do?
Alcohol is
the next best sedative.
Higher the proof. the better.
Not a goddamn chance.
Why don't you raid that magical
pantry you're so proud of?
That is food. Negan.
We need alcohol.
All right. you know what?
Just to be clear.
Dillard and I only care about
holding on to our shit
and not giving it away.
And while we're on the topic.
these people are clearly
only a threat to each other
and not our shit.
which makes this shit...
beyond the scope of shit that
we need to be
giving a shit about.
She's really hurting. man.
Fine. go get the damn whiskey.
I am gonna go have a smoke.
Hey. I appreciate what you
and Dillard are doing.
Alright. well. the more time
he gets to spend with people.
the less with corpses.
is a win for both of us.
So you're doing this for him?
You really don't give a shit?
Gold star. counselor.
You cracked the case.
You know. Maggie said
this was your idea.
-bringing in more people.
-Idea. sure.
Piss poor execution?
Hell no.
Look. I don't get
why we patch up people
and then let
them go kill each other.
You pick a side. you treat them.
you have their loyalty forever.
That is the safe play.
Well. the safest play
is to kill 'em all.
Well.
The lady has a good point.
Of course. then
who would plant the fields?
Who would fix the sewers?
Who would protect our homes?
Yes. I can make a choice
that would save us today.
But it might lead
to our deaths a month.
a year. a decade from now.
So I am not making any decision
until I have all the facts.
-My turn!
-Everything is fine.
Okay. it's just
a temporary loss in voltage.
This has happened before.
We'll be okay.
-He's in a lot of pain.
-I know.
We're gonna get something
for it.
Did Damien breathe in any smoke?
We all did.
-Belleville burnt down our home.
-Are you their leader?
Bauer said your people
started the fire.
Of course he did.
He's a liar and a monster.
Luis! He's having trouble
breathing.
It's Ray.
He's not doing so good.
Hershel. sterilize his
neck under his Adam's apple.
This guy's bleeding out fast.
I'm gonna have to get
him stabilized first.
Don't you dare.
Doctor's been treating
your people for the past
two hours.
Mine are dying.
The only person to blame is you.
Claudia.
They're dying because of you.
Help Damien.
Help him now.
Whether or not you threaten me.
I'm gonna help his people.
And I'm gonna help yours too.
Anyone who isn't
a hospital worker. a patient.
or a guard needs to leave
this ER immediately.
Let's go!
Hershel. I'm going
to treat this wound
while you do the cricothyrotomy.
-By myself?
-I'll guide you through it.
Look. cutting a throat open
sounds rough.
but it's a lot less complicated
than a compound fracture.
We can save both their lives.
but it means you have
to do this.
Okay.
Ellis. I need you
to take the Belleville people
to the apartments.
Rose. the Newark people
to the beach.
and I want five extra guards
on each.
And tell the team downstairs
to keep the tanks full.
The power cannot go out.
Do you understand?
Go.
Hey. just the two guards
I've been looking for.
Max down in the armory
is looking for both of you.
I will take these two.
Door over there.
Let's go.
Ray? That's your name. right?
Stay with me. Ray.
Can you tell me what happened?
Newark boy did that.
He put an arrow through
Ray's little girl and then
beat him with a crowbar.
He's here.
Ray. we've got to prevent
infection. stop blood loss.
and stabilize your fracture.
but we can't do that
until we manage your pain.
-You feel me?
-What is it?
I call that the Neil Armstrong.
It's mostly whiskey and Tang.
Alright.
Ready. Ray?
Drink as much as you can.
Hershel? Let's go.
I need you to feel for
the Adam's apple.
Move your fingers just below it.
That's
the cricothyroid membrane.
-You got it?
-Yeah. I got it.
Make the incision
just above that.
Talk to me. Hershel.
Can you feel the membrane?
-Yeah.
-Good.
Now you got to pierce it.
One breath. one motion.
Okay. Got it.
Now slide the tube in.
Doctor.
we need you over here.
I'll be over there soon.
Ray.
Ray?
Is he all right?
He passed out.
Pulse is good.
I think Ray's good.
We're good.
Can you check on bed eight?
I've got three more surgeries
to prep for.
Yeah.
She could have killed
my brother.
-Our only doctor.
-But we didn't let that happen.
Belleville outnumbers us.
So does Newark.
What if...
What if we heal them
only for one of them
to take over?
Completely wipe us out?
I know that I have
to make a choice here.
but what if there is
no right choice?
Anybody who tells you
that the solution's simple
is answering the wrong question.
Picking one side.
killing the other. that's easy.
Building a safe community is
the hardest thing in the world.
I don't know if there's
a right choice.
But if there is.
you're gonna make it.
This is what we asked for
when we turned on that light.
Do you regret doing it?
No.
Do you?
I should check on the new
arrivals in the apartment.
Hopefully I can get
some answers there.
Hey. you okay?
-Leonard!
-Yeah?
We're going on lockdown.
I want guards in the pantry
and the armory.
With everything happening.
we can't be too careful.
You got it.
Hey. guys!
We're going on lockdown!
Where the hell is Negan?
I'm gonna need you in
the armory.
Shoulda faced
the truth and just moved on.
Moved on how?
After you destroyed
everything we had?
Two groups of people.
But only one can stay.
However will we decide?
See. I used to know this...
Well. we'll call him an asshole.
And he would ask people
three questions.
and that would decide
whether or not
they would stay as part
of the community.
But see. I am not in the mood
to be asking any questions.
So we're gonna play a game.
We are gonna play Piñata.
And you two are stuffed full of
poo-poo-flavored candy.
Dillard!
See. Dillard. occasionally
you have to crack a couple eggs.
Otherwise. you're left
cleaning up
a big-ol' eggy mess.
I am tired of
the he said/she said bullshit.
So we're gonna let Dizzy Dillard
here take some swings
until one of you volunteer
to take your people out
of Manhattan.
Dillard?
♪ Dale. dale. dale! ♪
♪ You can't miss 'em.
Dillard ♪
♪ One of you is leaving.
or both of you are dead ♪
♪ Dale. dale. dale.
bashing in some heads ♪
Oh! Shh...
Oh! Oopsie-daisy.
Somebody forgot
to pay the power bill!
You know how we make
electricity?
Bodies.
That's right.
We live off the dead.
So unless one of you pipes up.
we will gladly kill
all of your people.
Seriously?
You would rather have your kids
power up my Xbox...
than squash this little
beef you have?
Alright. Got that.
Hey.
Hey. I'm comin'.
Oh. yeah. I feel this one.
Did you?
Oh. come on.
We just had a little bit of
a heart-to-heart is all.
Look. I don't know
who started it.
but neither asshole is innocent.
The war is not gonna end.
which means all we got
to do is...
Wow. Still?
-For reals with this?
-Christ.
How many guards does it take
to load a tank?
More.
What the hell
are they doing down there?
You are so gonna owe us.
No! No. wake up!
Please. stay!
Hershel. no!
I have to try.
All four ventilators
just went down.
If we don't Ambu bag. they're
brain dead in five minutes.
Here. bag Damien.
Can you do bed six?
-Yep.
-Ever done this before?
Once.
Connect it to
the breathing tube.
-Squeeze every six seconds.
-Every six seconds.
Mom. duck!
Bone saw. wall cabinet.
Here.
Please. Please.
Do you have anything
to give me for the pain?
It's the best I've got.
By the time I get down here...
They turned.
Must have got bit by a patient.
Alright. come on.
Dillweed. let's keep movin'.
Dillard.
Oh!
Aah! Get off me!
Aah!
-Help me! Help me!
-Stay under there!
Hey. man.
Oh. shit!
We should've stayed at the bar.
It's good to get out on the town
with you. man.
We need to bag bed three soon.
Hey. I know you're at war
with these two.
If they die. we all die.
Can't you help?
-Luis?!
-I got it!
Keep bagging!
Help me!
Help me! Help me!
-Hershel. did you hear that?
-Hear what?
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Hey.
What's up. Doc?
How am I supposed to
tell his family
he died from a broken arm?
We do it together.
We tell them it could have been
an embolism from the fracture
or something completely
unrelated.
a heart attack or aneurysm.
Because that's all we know.
Hey.
You lost a patient.
It hurts.
It'll always hurt.
Look at the people you saved.
Listen. I know this medical
school throws you right in.
and the student social life.
well. sucks.
But I will tell you.
you're gonna earn
a pretty kick-ass handwritten
certificate of doctorhood
from me.
Framed.
Bauer and Claudia.
they are locked
into this prick-measuring
contest of epic-ass proportions.
The fact of the matter is.
and I do know
you love your facts.
you can choose a group to stay
and send the other one off.
but it's just a matter
of time before the next attack.
So you let them
finish their little war.
Whichever group survives. stays.
You're right.
This war does have to end.
As long as these groups are
fighting each other.
Manhattan is at risk.
And yes. letting them battle
to the death.
that is a solution.
But it can't be the only one.
We three. we were enemies
when we first met.
Until the baby gave us
something to work for together.
We gotta give 'em something
to fight for.
Revenge is a cage.
The only escape comes from
putting our emotions aside.
These fields are enormous.
It will take each
and every one of your hands
to bring it to life.
Now. you can use these scythes
to turn on each other.
or you could use these scythes
to turn this parkland
into farmland.
Here. survival is not enough.
Here. together. we live.
Well. maybe she does got it.
I don't know what happened
across the river.
But your people are putting
it behind them.
Can you?
Hey.
Hershel was a star today.
You're a good teacher.
Thank you.
There you go. Steady.
-How many more are coming in?
-That's it.
Bauer and Claudia
couldn't move past.
But 146 out of 148 chose hope.
There's good people here.
And we saved a few of
them today.
No. You did.
They're alive because
you lit that light.
You took a chance.
You both did.
You were right to.
I've just been thinking
about Ramon.
Chucho.
Marisol.
The idea of losing someone else
is just...
Hey.
Luisito.
I know.
It's okay.
Yeah.
Yeah. It's gonna be.
I'm looking forward to
looking forward again.
Seeing you
at the hospital today.
you made me so proud.
You're working so hard.
I like it.
Do you? I can tell.
My daddy was a good man.
And I see so much of
his goodness in you.
This was his
and his father's before him.
And now it belongs to you.
Thank you.
Everything that you did today.
you're the best leader
that this place could have.
Youkept us all safe.
We're building the place
that we dreamed of.
It's... actually happening.
Which just makes it
so much scarier. right?
I've been in so many places
that didn't make it.
And this one is different.
If we can't make it work
with everything
that we've got going for us.
I don't think that we ever will.
I know.
But I also know that
we made it through today.
Yes. we did.
Tomorrow's going to look
so different.
With this many more people.
there's just so much more
to consider.
The hospital is almost out
of meds and methane.
We're gonna have
to schedule power outages.
And until we clear more blocks.
set up housing for everyone.
we're gonna need
something solid between us
and the walkers.
That's for tomorrow.
Let's take tonight
to appreciate today.
Can I be honest with you?
I cannot stand champagne.
It tastes like cat piss.
doesn't it?
It really does.
Oh. yes!
Much better.
Salud.
Mmm.
Holy meth lab. Crackman!
What is happening?
Ha ha!
Look. we may have lost
the whiskey.
but we are never gonna run out
of booze.
Just happened one
of those Belleville bastards
is also a bathtub gin wizard.
I like the sound of that.
What is happening in my bar?
-Well. I'm glad you asked.
-Okay.
-Follow me.
-With pleasure. brother.
Now don't get used to it.
I'm just giving
the Xbox the night off.
I did say you were gonna
get laid. right?
And you were on
a bit of a roll today.
So pick a girl.
Any girl.
Or boy. Whatever...
Whatever floats
your freaky boat.
I think I smell... methaney.
actually.
I should probably change
my clothes. bro.
-I'll be right back. Okay.
-Alright.
Okay.
He's turning you against us.
Against me.
Hey. stop it.
That man is no good.
I swear if I ever...
Hey. stop.
I'm sorry.
I get so jealous.
Stay with me tonight.
I said I can't. okay?
-Hey!
-Please.
-I miss you.
-No!
I love you.
Are you the traitor?
Can I help you?
We've come to make a deal.
This woman can get
her hands on anything.
You're sending
our only doctor away?
I need you
to make sure he's safe.
If I live here.
I have to live under your rules?
You follow the same rules
as everyone else.
If this is real.
it could be dangerous.
This is the start of
something better for everyone.
Hi. everyone. I'm Aimee Garcia.
I play Renata on "Dead City"
season three.
Welcome. Muah!
Renata is the leader
of her family.
When her father passed away.
she really had to step up
and take the reins.
And she also becomes
the leader of her community.
Everything The Croat had said
about this place is true.
It is a fortress.
The only thing
that we are missing is someone
who knows
how to keep things safe.
Maggie.
I've always loved that
character. and I always thought.
"Oh. we could be friends."
Now we get to be besties.
Let's take tonight
to appreciate today.
I had said to Seth.
"Please write a BFF for Maggie
because she's just been up
against it.
and it's like she's
been trying to carve her way
through this ocean of enemies
"it has felt like
for a few years."
You haven't had a gal pal.
-Right?
-Yeah.
They both are big-hearted
warriors.
I think there's a complete
mutual respect for each other.
They both have a natural
magnetic leadership quality.
And I think Renata brings out.
hopefully a light in Maggie.
too.
I cannot stand champagne.
It tastes like cat piss.
doesn't it?
It really does.
I just feel like you root
for this friendship.
Building a safe community is
the hardest thing in the world.
This is what we asked for
when we turned on that light.
What Renata brings
to the storyline
is this level
of heart and family and warmth
that has been missing
for our characters for so long.
Renata is charismatic.
she's levelheaded.
She's a total badass.
She actually has this weapon.
which I have personally named
Bonita because it is a bone saw.
This is my first time
with Renata's weapon
and I'm being sensei'd.
Go on.
I thought that name
would be very appropriate.
Bonita means "pretty"
in Spanish.
Lauren gave me a great tip
because she said. "You should
grunt when you kill a walker."
And she says it does
multiple things.
It warns the stunt person
that you're coming
and it also makes
you feel less awkward.
Tips from the pro.
I'm literally putting
my life in Lauren's hands.
Oh. shit!
Wow. The head fell
right towards the camera.
Lauren is amazing.
She is such a fearless leader
in real life.
She's a great quarterback
of this team.
I love her and I hope
to be friends with her
for a very long time.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today